YURII SHALIA

Poland, Krakow | +38099 725 35 40 | shalyayura@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/shalyayura

PROFILE

Tech savvy front-end developer with more than 6 years of experience in software development, including React, React Native, CSS3, API, and other libraries. Extensive knowledge in UI/UX, testing, optimization solutions and debugging processes, developed technical and architectural solutions. A team player who easily connects with any stakeholder, they are distinguished by their strong analytical capabilities and thriving collaborative teamwork skills.

KEY COMPETENCIES

- Responsive Design
- Build Tools
- UI/UX Principles

- Performance Optimization
- Software Development
- API Integration

- Testing and Debugging
- Problem-Solving
- Cross-Browser Compatibility

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Frontend Developer (Remote) at AltexSoft | Krakow, Poland

Nov 2023 - Apr 2024

- Made high-level contributions to team-leading site optimizations and also rewrote the project architecture by 18% with the ability to reuse components for further use in other modules of the project;
- Maintained the relevance of the dev-packages in the project and updated the React library to version 16 to 18 and optimized the project with new features;
- Designed and developed front-end vs back-end communication via REST API endpoints and queries;
- Tested the site for usability while addressing any bugs, mentored junior development team members.

Frontend Developer at Gentle Code | Kharkiv, Ukraine

Aug 2019 - Oct 2023

- Engineered responsive web applications optimizing the user experience on desktops, tablets, and mobile devices, increasing page load speed by 25%;
- Engineered visually striking and intuitive UI designs by optimizing code structure and implementing responsive design techniques;
- Implemented new features and refactored old functionality;
- Gathered and analyzed requirements from stakeholders to create clear and actionable development plans;
- Solve complex challenges using modern web application development processes and standard methodologies.

Internship JavaScript Developer at Sigma Software | Kharkiv, Ukraine

Feb 2019 - Jul 2019

- Collaborated with designers and back-end developers to create and maintain web applications;
- Developed front-end code using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript;
- Conducted user testing and troubleshooted technical issues;
- Participated in team meetings and contributed to project planning and execution;
- Assisted with the maintenance and updating of existing web applications.

Frontend Developer at Starlight.Space | Kharkiv, Ukraine

Jan 2018 - Dec 2018

- Worked with UI interface markup, ensuring visually appealing and user-friendly designs;
- Was in charge of creating responsive web applications that deliver a seamless user experience across various devices, including desktop, tablet, and mobile;
- Collaborated closely with design teams to implement design concepts into functional user interfaces, focusing on aesthetics and usability;
- Participated in the UX design process and reviewed technical feasibility;

EDUCATION

National Technical University "Kharkiv Polytechnic - Institute" | Kharkiv, Ukraine

Master diploma of Multimedia information Technologies and system.

2013 - 2019

Bachelor diploma of Multimedia information Technologies and system.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: English (Professional working proficiency/B2), Ukraine(native), Russian(native). Development:

• HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, Flexbox, Grid.

Application and web servers:

- JavaScript, TypeScript, ES6+, React 16+, Redux, React-Router, Redux-Form, Next.JS, React Hook Form, Lodash, Axios, Tanstack Query, Apollo GraphQL, JWT, WebSockets.
- React Native, Reanimated, React Navigation, API Routes, Zustand, Charts, Clerk.
- Webpack, GIT, Node.js, DevTools, Jest, Eslint, Husky.
- Bootstrap, React-Bootstrap, Tailwindcss, Ant-Design.
- Responsive design principles cross browsing, CodeReview, Jira, Agile, Scrum.